Downloaded from YTS.MX
‎NETFLIX 喜剧特辑
Official YIFY movies site: YTS.MX
Ladies, gentlemen, and everybody, put your hands together.
‎各位先生女士，让我们鼓掌鼓励
Please welcome to the stage Ali Wong!
‎欢迎黄艾莉上台！
Hi, everybody!
‎大家好！
We love you, Ali!
‎艾莉，我们爱你！
Thank you.
‎谢谢
You know, I'm very jealous and bitter
‎我最嫉妒和痛恨的
that when a man finds
‎就是当男人
any ounce of mainstream success in comedy,
‎在喜剧界得到一点点主流成就时
they get to date models,
‎就能泡到模特儿
actresses, and pop singers.
‎女演员和流行歌手
One of my dear friends is arguably one of the top stand-up comics
‎我一个好朋友可能是全世界脱口秀圈
in the world.
‎数一数二的大师
And for the past year and a half,
‎她过去一年半
she's been dating
‎交往的对象
a magician.
‎是个魔术师
I was like, "Okay, you know, no judgment, girl,
‎我就想：“好吧，不要随便批评别人
but is he at least, like, a good magician?"
‎但他至少是个很厉害的魔术师吧？
"Is he, like, the best magician
‎至少是最强的魔术师
like how you are one of the best stand-up comedians?"
‎配得上你这个顶尖脱口秀谐星吧？”
I looked that dude up on Yelp, he got two stars.
‎结果我上评价网站查，只有两颗星
That's what being one of the best female stand-up comics will achieve you.
‎女性脱口秀巨星也只能找到这种货色
A "ain't shit" magician.
‎“三流”魔术师
See, because when you are a woman with money, power, and respect,
‎因为如果你是有钱、有权 ‎又受人尊敬的女人
your romantic options do not expand.
‎交往对象范围并不会因此扩大
They decline!
‎反而缩小！
Now, I am told it's because men are threatened
‎听说这是因为女人 ‎有钱、有权又受人尊敬时
by women with money, power, and respect.
‎男人就会倍感威胁
What do you think is going to happen to you, huh?
‎你们以为自己会出什么事？
You think your dick is gonna get acquired in a hostile takeover?
‎自己的老二会受到恶意并购吗？
I bet most men in this theater
‎我猜这个剧院里大部分的男人
have never, ever had your dick sucked
‎都没让自己的老二
by a woman that makes a lot more money than you.
‎被比你更会赚钱的女人吹过
And let me tell you something.
‎我告诉你们
It is spectacular, okay?
‎绝对让你爽歪歪，好吗？
It is.
‎真的
‎我没骗你
Why wouldn't it be?
‎怎么不会？
If she got the skills to earn money, power, and respect,
‎如果她的能力强到 ‎能够有钱、有权又受人尊敬
you don't think she got good pattern recognition?
‎你觉得她会不知道怎么干吗？
Those skills transfer.
‎这种能力是可以转移的
You should feel so lucky,
‎你应该要觉得三生有幸
so flattered, so blessed and highly favored,
‎感到光荣、祖上积德、女神垂爱
if you ever had the opportunity to get your dick sucked
‎因为你竟然有这个机会 ‎能让自己的老二
by a woman that makes a lot more money than you.
‎被一个比你会赚钱很多的女人含住
Because out of all the things
‎因为这个重要的女人
this important woman could be doing with her valuable time…
‎明明可以把时间用在这么多事情上
Yeah.
‎对
All of her responsibilities,
‎她有这么多重责大任
all the interesting opportunities and deals knocking at her door,
‎这么多有趣的商机 ‎这么多合作机会送上门来
but no.
‎但她偏不要
She chose to get on her knees
‎而是宁愿跪下来
and stick your $40,000-a-year dick in her mouth…
‎把你一年才四万美元的老二含进嘴里
in your Toyota Yaris.
‎还在你的丰田小鸭里办事
But no. None of you,
‎但是没有，没有一个人
not a single man in here knows what it's like
‎在场没有一个单身男子知道
to cum on the face of a millionaire.
‎对着百万富翁颜射的感觉
Sure, you've gotten head.
‎没错，你有口交过
But have you ejaculated onto a great American mind?
‎但你射在美国精神领袖的脸上过吗？
Has your sperm swam in the eyes of an icon?
‎你的精子
‎有在风云人物的眼睛里游泳过吗？
Have you been deep-throated by a voice of a generation?
‎当代领袖有帮你吹过喇叭吗？
I don't think so!
‎我不信！
It's highly unlikely that any man in here…
‎这里不太可能有任何男人…
Well, any straight man in here,
‎这里不会有任何异性恋男人
knows what it's like to cum on the face of a millionaire.
‎知道射在百万富翁脸上的感觉
First of all, how many female, self-made millionaires are there to begin with?
‎首先，请问这世界上 ‎有几个白手起家的百万富婆？
And then out of that pool,
‎在这些人当中
how many of them gonna let you cum on their face?
‎又有几个人愿意让你颜射？
There's three of us, okay?
‎只有我们三个好吗？
Yeah, I don't even know who the other two are.
‎对，而且我还不知道另外两个是谁
You think Ellen gonna let you cum on her face?
‎你以为艾伦狄珍妮愿意让你颜射吗？
You think Oprah gonna let you go to Montecito and stomp on all her vegetables?
‎你以为欧普拉愿意让你 ‎跑去她家踩烂她的菜吗？
I love
‎我超爱
to get cummed on, on the face.
‎让男人射在脸上的
I do.
‎真的
Because it's so nasty
‎因为虽然超恶心
and is so easy.
‎但是超轻松
It is so easy, especially when you compare it to sucking dick,
‎超级轻松，尤其是和吹喇叭相比
which is so physically taxing.
‎真的超费体力
The choking, the eyes watering.
‎让你无法呼吸、泪流满面
And if you really want to keep it 100, you got to add the pepper grinding.
‎如果要满分，还得加上磨胡椒的动作
A lot, you know?
‎累死了，懂吗？
Whenever I get a deep tissue massage, the masseuse is always like,
‎我去做深层组织按摩时 ‎按摩师每次都会跟我说
"Do you sit and work at a computer all day?"
‎“你整天都坐在电脑前工作吗？”
I'm like, "No, I sucked dick last night."
‎我说：“不是，我昨晚吹喇叭
"Now I can't look to the left."
‎结果现在就不能看左边了”
So in addition to all of that labor,
‎除了这些粗活以外
when you suck dick, there is all of this performing and pretending involved.
‎吹喇叭时还要拼命演戏和假装
You have to tell all of these lies.
‎必须讲一堆谎话
"This is the biggest dick I've ever had in my mouth."
‎“我从来没含过这么大的鸡鸡”
"I love sucking your cock. It makes my pussy so wet."
‎“我好爱帮你吹喇叭，我鲍鱼超湿的”
"Yummy!"
‎“好吸…”
But you have to tell the lies
‎可是我非得讲这种谎话
to make the man cum faster.
‎才能让男人快点射出来
The lies will set you free!
‎说谎能让你海阔天空！
But then when you get cummed on on the face,
‎可是当对方射在你脸上时
your only job as the woman
‎身为女人，唯一的工作
is to make an enthusiastic expression.
‎就是摆出陶醉的表情
And then your other assignment
‎然后另一个任务
is to not laugh…
‎就是别笑出来
while this grown-ass man is straddling your rib cage,
‎这个大男人骑在你的胸口上时
he looking down at you, you looking up at him,
‎他往下看着你，你朝上看着他
and you see him from this very unflattering angle
‎用他最丑的角度看着他
where he got that Jabba the Hutt double chin, you know?
‎他挤出《星际大战》 ‎那个超肥外星人贾霸的双下巴
He all possessed by the Holy Spirit.
‎这时圣灵又附在他身上
"Look at me, Mommy, watch me, pay attention, look at me!"
‎“看着我，妈咪，看着我 ‎专心一点，看着我！”
Young men in particular,
‎年轻男人特别讨厌
they don't like women with money, power, and respect,
‎有钱、有权又受人尊敬的女人
because they know you can't tell that kind of woman what to do.
‎因为他们知道这种女人不会听话
Young men want a woman that's chill.
‎年轻男人喜欢好讲话的女人
That's a quality in a partner that they seek out and brag about.
‎他们最喜欢这种个性的伴侣
‎还会到处炫耀
"Bro, I'm dating this new chick."
‎“兄弟，我现在新交的马子
"She's so chill."
‎超好讲话的
"She doesn't give a fuck about what I do 'cause she's chill."
‎她根本不管我干嘛 ‎因为她很好讲话”
"She lets me do whatever I want 'cause she's dead inside."
‎“她让我随心所欲，因为她心已死
"She's chill."
‎她很好讲话”
"She's like a corpse with tits. It's awesome."
‎“她就像有奶子的死人，超赞的
"She's chill."
‎她很好讲话”
I have never, ever wanted to date a man that was chill.
‎我从以前就不想跟好讲话的男人交往
'Cause chill don't pay the bills.
‎因为好讲话的人赚不了钱
My nephew is 25 years old, and he is dating this architect.
‎我侄子今年25岁，女朋友是建筑师
My goodness, she is so smart and interesting,
‎天啊，她脑袋聪明，个性有趣
successful, and charismatic,
‎事业成功、魅力满点
and we all hope that he marries her one day.
‎我们都希望两人有一天会结婚
But he called me up earlier this week and he was like, "You know, Auntie Ali,
‎但他这个礼拜打给我说：“艾莉姑妈
I think I'mma break up with her."
‎我想跟她分手”
"Yeah, because she's a boss at work,
‎“对，因为她是公司老板
and so she thinks it's okay to come home and boss me around."
‎所以觉得可以对我管东管西”
I was like, "Oh."
‎我说：“喔”
"Well,
‎“这种事
that shit's gonna happen to you no matter what."
‎不管怎么样，你迟早都会碰到的”
"Whether she a boss, whether she employed or unemployed,
‎“不管她是公司老板、员工还是无业
once you get married and have kids,
‎一旦你们结婚生小孩
your wife gonna boss you around."
‎老婆就会对你管东管西
"And you would know that if you watched House Hunters."
‎只要你看过《买屋猎人》就会知道”
House Hunters is a show on HGTV
‎《买屋猎人》是居家乐活台的节目
where a couple
‎节目里的一对夫妻
pretends that there's a decision to be made together.
‎假装要一起做出决定
And they go on this fake-ass journey looking at three different houses,
‎他们踏上假到爆的路程，看三间房子
and the audience is meant to be left in suspense.
‎观众本来应该要很想知道
"Which house are they gonna choose?"
‎“他们到底会选哪间房子？”
It's whichever one Barbara wanted in the first place, okay?
‎拜托，绝对是芭芭拉 ‎一开始就想要的那间好吗？
And Barbara, who lives in Boise, Idaho,
‎芭芭拉住在爱达荷州的波夕市
or wherever the fuck these HGTV shows are filmed
‎或者居家乐活节目录影的鬼地方
where houses cost $5,000 an acre…
‎那里的房子每坪只要4美元
Barbara, she don't got money, power, or respect.
‎芭芭拉没钱、没权，也不受人尊敬
But Barbara is a woman,
‎但芭芭拉是个女人
and all women are very good
‎所有女人都很擅长
at being extremely unpleasant…
‎让大家过得超级不爽
and holding your happiness and self-esteem hostage
‎女人会牢牢掐住你的幸福与自尊
until we get what we fucking deserve, okay?
‎除非我们拿到 ‎自己应该拥有的东西，好吗？
Yes.
‎对
That is a superpower that we evolved
‎这是女人进化而来的超能力
to compensate for our lack of earning potential.
‎为了弥补我们缺乏赚钱本事的弱点
You can't tell any woman what to do,
‎你不能叫女人做这个做那个
so you might as well pick the bitch that will give you health insurance, okay?
‎所以最好挑个 ‎能给你健康保险的女人，好吗？
‎我知道为什么
I know exactly why
there's a disproportionate amount of men that do stand-up.
‎男人做脱口秀这一行的人多得离谱
It's all because of fan pussy.
‎这全都是因为有迷妹
We call them chuckle fuckers.
‎我们把这种人称为“笑干娘”
These poor, naive women who get dickmatized when they laugh.
‎这些可怜、天真的女人 ‎只要笑就会受到鸡鸡催眠
And fan pussy is so motivating
‎而且迷妹会给人超强的动力
because fan pussy is young and sexy and exciting.
‎因为迷妹年轻、火辣又刺激
Fan pussy is a great reward for doing stand-up comedy.
‎迷妹是表演脱口秀的一大好康
And fan dick
‎但是迷哥
is frightening.
‎就很吓人
Any man watching me, listening to what I have to say,
‎哪个男人要是看我长相，听我讲话
and thinking to themselves, "I want to fuck her…"
‎心里还会想：“我要干爆她”
is a raging psychopath.
‎那绝对是超级神经病
And has extremely good taste.
‎而且超级有品味
Fan dick is not interested in showing me a good time.
‎迷哥并不想让我过得开心
Fan dick wants to trim my pubes
‎迷哥只想帮我修剪阴毛
and sew them into wigs for his antique doll collection.
‎然后编成假发，当成古董娃娃收藏品
That's why I don't see more women doing stand-up.
‎所以很少女人在做脱口秀
There is no reward,
‎根本就没有好处
only danger and punishment.
‎只会带来危险和伤害
Lot of my male stand-up comic friends be hooking up with women,
‎我很多做脱口秀的男性朋友 ‎都能透过社群媒体的私讯
beautiful, gorgeous women, through the DMs.
‎交到貌美如花的美眉
Direct messaging.
‎“私讯”就是私人讯息
I never check my DMs.
‎我从来不看私讯的
And when I do, it's only to see if Sanrio, the owners of Hello Kitty,
‎我看私讯只是想知道 ‎拥有凯蒂猫商标的三丽鸥公司
have finally contacted me to offer sponsorship.
‎有没有总算跟我联络，提供赞助
Yeah.
‎对
Come on!
‎拜托！
I think I'd be a great fit, and I want all of that shit.
‎我觉得我很适合 ‎而且我爱他们的周边商品
I want the Gudetama pajamas.
‎我要蛋黄哥睡衣
I want the erasers that smell like the gum.
‎我要闻起来像口香糖的橡皮擦
And I want the gum that tastes like the erasers.
‎还有嚼起来跟橡皮擦一样的口香糖
I want all of that shit.
‎我最爱那种鬼东西
But no.
‎但是没有
My DMs are full of
‎我的私讯全都是
these Silence of the Lambs motherfuckers.
‎《沉默的羔羊》那种操他妈变态
It's these dudes who always have zero followers.
‎这种人一定没人追踪
Do you know anybody who doesn't know anybody?
‎你们谁认识一个朋友都没有的人？
They don't even offer to take me out to dinner
‎他们甚至没说要请我吃饭
or lick my pussy.
‎或者舔我的鲍鱼
They just threaten to decapitate me if I don't let them smell my feet.
‎他们只威胁要砍我的头 ‎除非他们能闻我的脚丫
And it's a shame, you know?
‎很可惜，你们知道吗？
It's very disturbing, this disparity in quality
‎迷妹和迷哥之间的本质差异
between fan pussy and fan dick.
‎真的很吓人
It is so upsetting
‎那种感觉
to a person like me.
‎让我非常胆战心惊
Because I think
‎因为我有想过
about cheating on my husband…
‎让我老公戴绿帽子…
every five minutes.
‎每五分钟就有这个念头
I haven't done it yet.
‎但我还没出轨…现在还没有
Not because I'm a good person,
‎并不是因为我是个好人
only because no worthy opportunity has presented itself.
‎只是因为还没出现让我看对眼的人
My mom doesn't understand, she can't relate
‎我妈无法了解，她无法体会
to these feelings of wanting to fool around outside of your marriage,
‎结了婚还想到处尝鲜的感觉
because she's an immigrant woman who was born in 1940.
‎因为她是1940年出生的移民女性
Her world is a lot smaller than mine.
‎她的世界比我小很多
The only men my mother has ever had an actual conversation with
‎我妈只跟两个男人真的好好讲过话
are my brother and my dad. That's it.
‎一个是我哥，一个是我爸，没了
I, on the other hand,
‎至于我
have met the entire cast of The Avengers.
‎却见过《复仇者联盟》的所有演员
And I want all of them to cum on my face.
‎而且我希望他们全都射在我脸上
I think I'm going through a mid-life crisis.
‎我好像碰上中年危机了
Having two C-sections and being the breadwinner of my family
‎我剖腹生产两次，又是经济支柱
has turned me into a 50-year-old man.
‎结果让我变成50岁的男人
I had a colonoscopy a couple years ago.
‎我几年前做过大肠镜检查
That is some 50-year-old man shit right there.
‎这就是50岁男人的症头
What had happened was
‎事情经过是
I, all of a sudden, got extremely bloated over a very short period of time.
‎我突然在非常短的时间内整个人爆肥
And it was so extreme to the point where I thought I was pregnant again.
‎严重到我以为我又怀孕了
And I took a test, and it was negative.
‎所以我去检查，结果没有
And then my OBGYN became very concerned
‎但是我的妇产科医生非常担心
that I was showing symptoms of ovarian cancer,
‎这是卵巢癌的症状
because it runs in my family.
‎因为这是家族遗传
And so then she ordered a CT scan, and the results came back.
‎然后她安排电脑断层扫描，结果出来
And she said to me,
‎她跟我说
"Okay, Ali."
‎“好，艾莉
"Well, you know, the good news is that
‎好消息是
you don't have ovarian cancer, okay? And then…"
‎你没有卵巢癌，好吗？但是…
"The bad news is that, Ali,
‎坏消息是，艾莉
you are full of shit."
‎你满肚子大便”
"Stop giggling, Ali, stop it. This is serious, okay?"
‎“艾莉，别笑，这件事很严重好吗？”
On the report, the radiologist wrote,
‎放射科医师在报告上写
"The results are remarkable."
‎“检查结果很惊人”
Which, to me, seems like the radiologist gave me an A++.
‎我以为放射科医师给我甲上苹果苹果
She was like, "No, that's bad."
‎结果她说：“不对，这很严重”
When the radiologist writes "The results are remarkable,"
‎如果放射科医师写“检查结果很惊人”
what that translates to is,
‎白话文的意思就是
"Oh my goodness,
‎“我的天啊
I don't understand how this tiny Vietnamese mom
‎真不知身材这么娇小的越南人母
fit this football field of doo-doo inside of her body."
‎怎么装得下能放满足球场的便便？
"I have never seen this in my 30 years as a radiologist,
‎我干放射科医师30年都没见过这种事
and I cannot wait to text screenshots of this to all my radiologist friends."
‎好想赶快拍下来 ‎传给每一个放射科医师同行”
So then a GI specialist was called in,
‎所以他们找了肠胃科医师
and I saw her look at the results,
‎我看她看检查报告的表情
and she went like this.
‎是这样
And then she turns to me and says,
‎然后她转过头来看着我说
"Miss Wong, I am so sorry that I gasped in front of your face."
‎“黄小姐，真对不起 ‎我竟然在你面前露出惊讶表情
"That was so unprofessional of me."
‎实在太不专业了
"I know exactly who you are."
‎我知道你是谁
"Please do not talk about how I just did that on stage."
‎拜托你别拿我刚才的行为当笑话讲”
"But, you know, I have to admit that I'm clearly alarmed by what I see here."
‎“可是我也得承认 ‎报告内容真的让我很惊恐
"You are backed up well into your small intestine,
‎你的粪便已经一路塞到小肠
and I'm almost certain that there is some sort of mass,
‎我几乎能确定有肿块在那边
and most likely a tumor that's causing all of this blockage."
‎很可能是肿瘤导致肠道堵塞
"So we're going to have to perform a colonoscopy
‎所以我们要做大肠镜
to see what's going on in there."
‎看看里面是什么情形”
I was like, "Why? You guys just did a CT scan."
‎我说：“为什么？ ‎你们刚刚做过电脑断层扫描耶”
And she was like, "Yes,
‎她说：“对
it is true that the whole point of a CT scan is to see inside of your body,
‎电脑断层扫描的目的 ‎的确是透视体内状况
but the lasers couldn't penetrate the Great Wall of Shit that's inside you."
‎但是雷射光穿不过你体内的大便长城
"And they just ricocheted and bounced back into the machine,
‎雷射光反弹折射回机器本身
and now the machine is shook, so…
‎结果机器现在秀逗了，所以…
we're going to have to stick a camera
‎我们要拿摄影机
up your ass."
‎插你肛门”
And I was so nervous.
‎我超紧张
But what I didn't know was that right before the procedure,
‎但是我不知道在大肠镜检查开始之前
they give you propofol.
‎会先打麻醉药
And I have to say that as a working mother of two…
‎我得说，身为有两个小孩的职业妇女
getting to take a drug-induced nap for an hour…
‎能在打麻药后睡个一小时…
was well worth having a news crew up my butt.
‎让人进我肛门现场转播实在太划算了
It was luxurious.
‎至高无上的享受
When I woke up from the colonoscopy, I was like,
‎我做大肠镜麻醉醒来后，马上说
"I want another colonoscopy."
‎“我要再做一次大肠镜”
And then it turned out that my colon was perfectly healthy,
‎结果我的大肠非常健康
and I figured out that what caused that huge traffic jam was
‎我知道我体内为什么会交通大打结了
the summer before, I was shooting this movie called Always Be My Maybe.
‎因为我前一年夏天 ‎在拍《可能还爱你》电影
Oh, thank you.
‎谢谢各位
Yeah, it was a big-ass deal because it was the first movie I had ever co-written
‎对，这部电影非常重要 ‎因为这是我第一部担任共同编剧
and starred in as the lead.
‎而且领衔主演的电影
And I worked on it for 12 hours a day,
‎我一天工作整整12个小时
every day for six weeks straight, and I was so busy
‎而且连续工作六周不间断，超级忙
that I forgot to take a shit…
‎忙到我忘了要大便…
for six weeks.
‎整整六个星期
The movie shot in Vancouver and in San Francisco,
‎电影是在加拿大温哥华 ‎和美国旧金山拍摄
and I have no recollection of shitting in Vancouver or in San Francisco.
‎但我完全不记得 ‎在温哥华或旧金山有撇过条
I just straight up forgot.
‎我完完全全忘记了
Something like that would never happen to a man.
‎这种事情绝对不可能发生在男人身上
Men, you never forget to take a shit ever.
‎男人绝对不会忘记大便
Ever.
‎想太多
How could you, when you sit on the toilet and have your sacred ritual
‎不可能，因为你每天早上都霸占马桶
every morning to summon the shit?
‎进行你的神圣仪式，召唤大便
You sit there from 8:00 a.m. to 8:30 a.m.
‎你们都从早上8点坐到8点半
You sit there with all of your reading materials,
‎坐在那边，准备好所有要看的东西
your iPad battery just burning up the sperm in your balls.
‎平板电脑的电池烫到 ‎连蛋蛋里的精虫都熟了
You sit there at the most crucial time of the day,
‎你刚好在一天最重要的时间霸占马桶
when your wife and kids need you and the bathroom the most.
‎在老婆、孩子最需要你和厕所的时候
You sit there to avoid reality and all of your responsibility in life.
‎你坐在那里逃避现实 ‎以及人生的所有责任
You're too scared to ask your wife for alone time,
‎你怕到不敢跟老婆要求独处时间
so instead you just passively-aggressively take it
‎所以就以被动的方式强取豪夺
by chasing your wife and kids out of the bathroom
‎用你自私到爆的大便臭味
with the stank of your selfish-ass shit!
‎把老婆、孩子赶出厕所！
Women, we don't do that, okay?
‎我们女人不会这样干好吗？
We have too much guilt and shame
‎我们心中有太多内疚和耻辱感
to sit there every morning at the same time to summon the shit.
‎不敢每天早上在固定时间召唤大便
Instead, the shit comes to us
‎但是大便会跑来找我们
at the most inconvenient time of the day.
‎而且专挑一天中最不方便的时间
When we're in the middle of a meeting, or
‎例如开会到一半，或者
onstage taping our third Netflix special.
‎上台录第三个Netflix喜剧特辑时
But when you feel that first turtle head peek out,
‎但是等你觉得黄金先生快要出头时
you gotta squeeze your butt cheeks in,
‎必须夹紧两片屁股
suck the poo-poo back up
‎把便便吸回到
into your generous, loving, self-sacrificing soul.
‎你那慷慨、慈悲又自我牺牲的灵魂里
But then at some point, you gots to go,
‎但是到了某个时候，该上的还是得上
and then it's an emergency.
‎这时就变成紧急状况了
It's always an emergency when a woman finally takes a shit,
‎女人终于撇条时，一定是紧急状况
and that's why every woman's public restroom
‎所以每个女人的公共厕所
looks like a post-apocalyptic zombie nightmare,
‎看起来就像末日后的僵尸恶梦场景
where there is blood on the walls and pizza on the record player.
‎墙上有血迹，黑胶唱盘上还有披萨
My life has changed dramatically in the past seven years.
‎我过去这七年的生活变化很大
Seven years ago, I pressured the shit out of my then-boyfriend to propose to me.
‎七年前，我用尽拉屎的力气 ‎逼我当时的男友跟我求婚
Every day, I was in his ear…
‎我每天都在他的耳边说
"When you going to ask me to marry you?"
‎“你什么时候才要跟我求婚？
"I'm not gonna wait forever!"
‎老娘可不会等你一辈子！
"Everybody wants this pussy."
‎每个人都想要这个鲍鱼”
Nobody else wanted this pussy,
‎其实根本没别人想搞我
but I had to make up these fairy tales
‎但我总得编这种童话故事
to add pizzazz to the ultimatum, you know?
‎才能在下最后通牒时 ‎多点筹码，懂吗？
It was crazy, but my wish came true.
‎实在太扯了，可是我的美梦成真
He proposed, we got married.
‎他求婚，我们结婚
We bought a house, had two kids.
‎我们买了一间房子，生了两个小孩
Fast-forward to seven years later, present day, I'm like,
‎快转到七年后的现在，我心想
"I don't know why I did that."
‎“我当初何苦呢？”
I think that what happened was at the time,
‎我觉得关键在于那个时候
my future in comedy was looking very uncertain, you know?
‎我在喜剧界的未来非常黯淡，懂吗？
I was really struggling.
‎我做得真的很不好
Like, I was eating cough drops for dessert.
‎穷到把喉糖当甜点吃
It was so sad.
‎超可悲的
And I panicked. I was like, "I don't know if I can make it in this world on my own."
‎我心一慌就想：“我不知道 ‎能不能靠自己立足这个世界
"So I better trap this dude who graduated from Harvard Business School
‎所以最好先把这个 ‎哈佛商学院的高材生骗到手
so that I don't end up homeless."
‎免得将来无家可归”
But now,
‎结果现在
I know that I can make it on my own.
‎我知道我可以自立更生了
So I kind of want to just be on my own.
‎所以我有点想自立更生
Only other married people with kids can empathize
‎只有其他已经生小孩的夫妻才能了解
with the deep envy I feel towards you single people, okay?
‎我有多嫉妒 ‎你们这些单身贵族，好吗？
You don't know how free you are.
‎你们不知道自己有多自由
You can eat an edible at 2:00 p.m.,
‎你们可以在下午2点吃大麻食品
go to the aquarium and watch the jellyfish go back and forth.
‎跑去水族馆看水母漂过来、漂过去
You don't gotta bring a giant bag with little Ziploc baggies of Goldfish,
‎你们不必带超大包包 ‎里面用小夹链袋装金鱼饼干
and toy cellphones.
‎还有玩具手机
You can just go with what's in your pockets.
‎不必多带东西就可以出门
You single people, you don't know what it's like
‎你们这些单身贵族都不知道
to eat a cold quesadilla
‎冷掉的墨西哥酥饼是什么味道
that your toddler threw on the floor,
‎因为你的小小孩把酥饼丢在地上后
because it's easier to put it in your mouth
‎放进嘴巴比跑去垃圾桶
than travel to the trash,
‎还要简单多了
while you repeat to yourself over and over that
‎你还得同时反覆告诉自己
child abuse is illegal!
‎虐待儿童是违法的！
You single people, if you're romantically involved with somebody,
‎你们这些单身贵族如果跟某个人交往
and then all of a sudden,
‎结果突然间
that somebody reveals a personality trait that you don't like,
‎发现你不喜欢某个人的个性
you could just leave.
‎这时只要走人就好
Move to another city and never see their stupid face again.
‎你可以搬到其他地方 ‎永远不必看到对方那张笨脸
Because you didn't make a promise
‎因为你没有山盟海誓
in front of your grandma and all your coworkers
‎向奶奶和所有同事挂保证
and ask your friends to buy you an Instant Pot.
‎还请朋友买电子压力锅送你
You didn't fuse your DNA to create human life that will forever ask you,
‎你不必混合自己的DNA ‎创造出一个生命，小孩还一直问你
"Where's Daddy?"
‎“爸爸在哪里？”
You single people, you don't have to go on a playdate,
‎你们这些单身贵族不必搞“游戏约会”
which is basically a blind date that your toddler sets you up on…
‎也就是你的小小孩 ‎帮你安排的相亲活动
with some bitch you have zero chemistry with.
‎对方是跟你完全没话聊的女人
You single people, you don't have to be nice to your mother
‎你们这些单身贵族不必对妈妈好
because you need her for babysitting.
‎因为你们需要她帮忙带小孩
You don't have to smile
‎你们不必陪笑
and listen to all of this unsolicited parenting advice
‎并且听她强迫推销育儿心法
from this woman who neglected the shit out of you…
‎这个女人以前养你时根本就放生耶
because you want time to yourself to binge Bridgerton to feel alive again.
‎你忍气吞声只是为了 ‎想找时间狂看《柏捷顿家族》
‎让自己觉得又活起来了
Like you single people, I, too, was once free, okay?
‎我跟你们这些单身贵族一样
‎也自由过，好吗？
And then like an idiot, I asked this dude to ask me to go to prison.
‎结果我白痴到要这个家伙请我坐牢
And now I'm in monogamy jail, and I don't know how to get out.
‎现在关在一夫一妻制的牢笼里
‎不知道怎么出来
Monogamy made sense when we lived until we were 40 years old.
‎一夫一妻制在我们40岁以前都很合理
Yeah, I'm 39 right now,
‎对，我现在39岁了
so if you told me that I had to do this shit for another year,
‎所以如果你跟我说我还要再坐一年牢
I'd be like, "Yeah, I could do that."
‎我会说：“好，我办得到
"I can rub it out to Aquaman for another year, it's fine."
‎我可以再边看《水行侠》 ‎边磨豆浆一年，可以的
"It's no big deal."
‎没什么”
But as an Asian woman, I'm gonna live
‎可是身为亚裔妇女，我可能会
until I'm 95 years old.
‎活到95岁
That's not even a joke, okay?
‎这不是笑话好吗？
that is statistically probable.
‎这在统计学上是可能的
My husband and I are the same age.
‎我老公跟我同龄
He'll most likely die when he's 85.
‎他很可能活到85岁
So between 85 and 95 is
‎所以社会规范允许我
when I'm morally allowed to fuck other people again.
‎在85岁到95岁之间再跟别人打炮
It's too late.
‎实在太晚了
'Cause at the age of 75 is when Asian women
‎因为亚裔妇女到了75岁时
finally turn into an owl.
‎会变成猫头鹰
You know what I'm talking about.
‎你们都知道我在讲什么
Their tattooed eyebrows turn green and shit.
‎她们的纹眉会变成超丑的绿色
They go bald, and then the few strands that are left, they perm the shit out of
‎头发掉光，剩下的几撮还会烫过头
to make it more Jhirmack "bounce back."
‎看起来就像洗发精的“回春”广告
And then they become obsessed with dried jujubes
‎而且她们爱吃红枣到走火入魔的地步
and just walk around in down jackets all day like this.
‎然后穿着羽绒外套，成天这样走路
I want to fuck other people now…
‎我现在就想跟别人烧干
before I metamorphosize into a nut sack with a visor.
‎非得赶在我变成戴眼罩的阴囊之前
You want to cheat with me?
‎想跟我一起偷人吗？
You want to fuck around with me?
‎想跟我一起乱搞吗？
You better give me two weeks' notice, okay?
‎那就最好提早半个月跟我说，好吗？
'Cause you gotta give me time to go shopping
‎因为你得给我时间去买
for new underwear.
‎新内裤
I've been with the same dude for the last 10 years.
‎我这十年都跟同一个人在一起
So all my underwear looks like it's been snacked on by rats.
‎所有的内裤看起来都像被老鼠啃过
Just looks like wardrobe from Les Miserables, okay?
‎就像《悲惨世界》的戏服，好吗？
Like a tattered sail of a pirate ship.
‎就像海盗船那种破破烂烂的帆
The elastic? Gone.
‎弹性呢？没了
So the crotch area hangs about five inches below my actual pussy,
‎所以裤裆部位 ‎距离真正的鲍鱼大概12公分
like a Indiana Jones suspension bridge,
‎就像《印第安纳琼斯》电影里的吊桥
like a hammock in the Blue Bayou, okay?
‎就像蓝色海湾里的吊床，好吗？
You want to fuck around with me? Let me know,
‎想跟我乱搞吗？先让我知道
so I got time to go to Target and get that sweet five-for-20 Xhilaration panty deal.
‎好给我时间去平价百货 ‎抢购打折的量贩包内裤
Merona, whatever's on sale.
‎或者Merona内裤，反正有打折就好
In our society,
‎在美国社会里
there is no word for a male mistress.
‎没有情夫这个词
That's how taboo it is for women to cheat on their husbands.
‎这就证明女人偷吃是多大的禁忌
The only word I've ever heard is sancho,
‎我只听过西班牙文“sancho”
yes, because Mexican women cheat on their husbands,
‎对，因为墨西哥女人会给老公戴绿帽
because their culture is mucho más mejor.
‎因为他们的文化“先进得多”
Es la verdad, okay? It is.
‎“真的”，好吗？真心不骗
I've been saying this about Mexican people and Mexican culture for a long time.
‎我老早这么说 ‎墨西哥人和墨西哥文化了
I'm like the Little Mermaid.
‎我就像小美人鱼
I want to be part of your Telemundo, okay?
‎想加入拉丁美洲的世界，好吗？
Yes. Si se puede, con permiso, let me in. Come on.
‎对，“如果可能的话” ‎麻烦让我加入，拜托
I like Fabuloso, okay?
‎我喜欢墨西哥清洁剂，好吗？
I like storing my pots and pans in the oven. Yeah.
‎我喜欢把锅子放进烤箱，对
I like squeezing lime juice on everything.
‎我不管吃什么都爱洒莱姆汁
I like hickeys. I love hickeys.
‎我喜欢种草莓，超爱种草莓
Generally, our society is very unforgiving
‎通常美国社会对于背叛丈夫的女性
of women who cheat on their husbands,
‎都非常没有包容心
and at the same time, it's so forgiving of men who cheat on their wives.
‎但是却非常包容背叛老婆的男性
Somehow money, power, and respect will earn a man the right to cheat.
‎所以有钱、有权又受人尊敬的男人
‎就有出轨的权利
People will come to his defense and say,
‎大家自然会帮这个人讲话
"Oh, how could he be expected to resist all of that fan pussy?"
‎“喔，他怎么抗拒得了这么多迷妹？
"He is so awesome, he deserves to cheat."
‎他这么厉害，当然有出轨资格”
For women, no matter how much money, power, or respect you earn,
‎至于女人，不管多么有钱 ‎有权又受人尊敬
you are never allowed to behave badly and get away with it.
‎都不能有负面行为 ‎而且一定要付出代价
But that's all I want to do.
‎但这就是我的最大心愿
I want to have it all.
‎我什么都想要
I want to have a family, a career,
‎我想要有家庭、事业
and a side piece.
‎还有小王
The greatest trick women ever played on ourselves was making us believe
‎女人对自己洗脑所说的最大谎言
‎就是让我们相信
that having it all was limited to having a family and a career.
‎人生胜利组的意义 ‎只限定在能兼顾家庭与事业
I got both of those things.
‎这两样我都有了
Newsflash, it's not enough.
‎我告诉各位，这是不够的
Necesito más.
‎“我要的不只这些”
I don't just want equal pay,
‎我不只要同工同酬
I want equal pleasure.
‎我还要同等的快乐
But it would be very threatening
‎但是如果女人都有这种要求
if all women wanted and felt like they deserved that,
‎而且觉得自己有这种资格 ‎造成的威胁就会太大
because then a bunch of women wouldn't be available
‎因为到时就会少了一堆女人
to helping their husbands make their lives as easy as possible.
‎帮自己的丈夫过得轻松又快活
Do you know how much more successful I would be if I had a wife?
‎你们知道如果我有老婆 ‎我会有多成功吗？
Some loving, devoted woman by my side
‎这样就有爱我又勤劳的女人在旁边
who bought a bunch of fruit besides bananas?
‎拿香蕉以外的一堆水果给我吃
And put the duvet cover on the duvet?
‎还会在棉被外面装被套
People don't like it when women cheat, you know,
‎大家都不喜欢女人外遇
and they'll really turn on you because they feel betrayed,
‎而且他们会拿你当箭靶 ‎因为觉得自己遭到背叛
especially if you're a mom.
‎你有小孩时更是如此
It's too contrary to your wholesome, loving image.
‎这会大大违背你的整体母爱形象
And that's why I'm trying to let all of you know now…
‎所以我现在要让各位知道
that I'm a real piece of shit, okay?
‎我真的是个烂人，好吗？
I want you to really listen to me and understand this and believe me,
‎我要你们好好听我说 ‎了解这件事，并且相信我
so that you're not shocked or surprised,
‎以免太过震惊或惊讶
so that you don't abandon me
‎最后抛弃我
when you see the TMZ video of my face getting fire-hosed by Michael B. Jordan…
‎因为八卦媒体可能哪天公开 ‎麦可B乔丹射在我脸上的影片
while I chant, "Wakanda forever!"
‎而且我还开心大喊：“瓦甘达万岁！”
I think another reason why a lot of women are hesitant to cheat
‎很多女人不敢偷吃的另一个原因
is because it's too high stakes
‎应该是代价太高
to put your family, your reputation,
‎因为你的家庭、名声
your life as you know it on the line,
‎和生活都会受到牵连
all for the probability that you most likely
‎更何况你很有可能
will not have an orgasm.
‎根本达不到高潮
Very difficult to make a woman, especially a new woman, cum.
‎女人，尤其是 ‎你还没上过的女人，很难高潮
It's so annoying.
‎真的很烦耶
It's a design flaw.
‎这根本就是设计缺陷
There's too many factors.
‎原因太多了
There's too much shit that has to align.
‎有太多条件必须满足
The lighting,
‎像是灯光
the temperature,
‎气温
the news.
‎还有新闻
You can't be all up in your head about the global supply chain being backed up.
‎你不能整个脑子都在想 ‎全球供应链大塞车的问题
I don't deserve to cum when the Dow Jones is down 500 points
‎道琼指数重挫500点 ‎而且我还不懂加密货币
and I still don't understand what cryptocurrency is.
‎这样的我怎么可以高潮呢？
Who can cum in times like these?
‎谁能在这个时间点高潮？
So in order for a woman to cum, all this shit has to align, right?
‎所以为了让女人高潮 ‎需要天时、地利、人和，对吧？
And then on top of that, the dude got to have skills.
‎除此之外，男人也要有技巧
He gotta have great timing.
‎他必须抓准进场点
He gotta know how to come in real slow and soft
‎必须知道一开始进去时 ‎动作要慢、要轻柔
and romantic and tenderoni in the beginning…
‎而且要浪漫、体贴
and then get real rapey by the end.
‎快结束时感觉要很像强暴
In, like, a consensual way, of course.
‎当然是要两情相悦啊
But a lot of dudes, they fuck that timing up, right?
‎但是很多男的都乱搞时间，对吧？
They come out the gates guns blazing,
‎一猛虎出闸就狂抽猛送
like Braveheart coming over the hill, just…
‎像《英雄本色》里遍地开花，然后…
"Mortal Kombat!"
‎变成《真人快打》游戏！
And you're like, "Okay, I'm bleeding and…
‎结果你说：“好，我流血了，而且…
think you rubbed my clit off onto the floor,
‎我的阴蒂被你磨断掉到地上
and now it's lost with the dust bunnies."
‎混进一堆灰尘里了”
And then some dudes, they do the opposite, right?
‎有的男人完全相反，对吧？
They maintain this whole, like, candlelit, walk-on-the-beach energy…
‎他们会把整个行程跑完 ‎像是烛光晚餐、海边漫步
Close your eyes Make a wish
‎闭上你的眼睛，许下心愿
…throughout the entire course of the sex, and it's like,
‎在整个爱爱期间都不松懈，但是
"Nah, dude. In the last 30 seconds,
‎“不对，老兄，最后30秒时
I need you to put me in a headlock
‎我要你扣住我的脖子
and say racist shit to me. Okay?"
‎然后对我说种族歧视的话，好吗？”
"Yeah."
‎“对”
"Yeah, I want my eyebrows to fly off my face,
‎“对，我要让假眉毛喷出我的脸
and I want you to degrade me until I go deaf and mute at the same time."
‎我要你贬低我的人格 ‎直到我又聋又哑为止”
"You gotta shape-shift, bro."
‎“你也必须会变形”
Nothing more satisfying to a woman
‎如果要让女人满意，最好的办法
then when a man goes through a sudden and extreme transformation
‎就是让她知道自己让一个男人
that she is responsible for.
‎突然变成另一个人
You know,
‎其实喔
would be such a shame to go through all that trouble of cheating
‎如果历经千辛万苦，好不容易偷吃了
to end up having to fake an orgasm.
‎还得假装自己高潮，实在很丢脸
In fact, I don't think any of us women should be faking orgasms anymore.
‎其实我觉得我们女人 ‎不应该再假装高潮了
Yeah.
‎对
No more faking orgasms.
‎别再假装高潮了
I mean, you really think about it, that is some nutty-ass shit
‎你们真的要好好想想我们女人
that we women do.
‎干的那些屁事
That's a skill that you taught yourself.
‎这是我们无师自通的技巧
That wasn't passed down to you from your mother.
‎并不是妈妈传授给你的
You taught yourself to do that shit out of survival.
‎你会无师自通，只是为了活下去
And it is wildly indicative of how terrified we women are
‎这件事更证明了我们女人有多害怕
of offending a man,
‎冒犯男人
that we would rather fake an orgasm than simply say…
‎我们宁愿假装有高潮，也不敢直接说
"Hey, I just want to go home."
‎“喂，我只想回家”
"This is so not awesome."
‎“我超级不爽的”
"And I feel like I've really tried to tell you where to put it,
‎“我真的已经想办法告诉你洞在哪里
where not to put it, how fast, how slow, and
‎洞不在哪里、要多快、多慢
you straight up just don't listen, you know, so…
‎但你就是不受教，所以…
I'd really like to just go back to my house and fold clothes."
‎我现在真的只想回家摺衣服”
Men are so much more incentivized to cheat because
‎男人出轨的诱因大得多，因为
you're going to cum no matter what.
‎你们无论如何都会射
It's so easy for a man to cum.
‎男人要射太简单了
All you need is a wet hole.
‎只要有会湿的洞就可以
You don't even need that!
‎其实连那个也不用！
Men love to jerk off in front of women all the time.
‎男人超爱在女人面前自慰的
I've seen, like, 70 men jack off in my lifetime.
‎我这辈子大概看过70个男人打手枪
Men love to show you their masturbation practice.
‎男人超爱让你看他们怎么自摸
But for me, you know,
‎但是对我来说
if a man is not performing at the caliber I need him to perform at,
‎如果男人的表现达不到我设定的标准
I'm not all of a sudden going to leap onto his neck
‎我并不会突然跳到他的脖子上
and start fingering myself over his face, you know?
‎然后在他的面前抠屄，你懂吗？
Like, "Oh, you have erectile dysfunction?"
‎“你有勃起障碍是吧？
"No problem. I got it."
‎没问题，交给我
"Let me just dangle my pubes,
‎让我把我的阴毛
my long-ass pandemic pubes over your forehead
‎我超长的浓密阴毛，悬在你额头前面
and squirt into your nose hole. You don't like it?"
‎然后潮吹到你鼻孔里，不喜欢吗？
"Who cares? Who's gonna believe you, you young, powerless boy?"
‎谁鸟你啊？谁会相信 ‎你这个没力的年轻人？”
I'd be like, "What the fuck am I doing?"
‎我会说：“我他妈的搞屁啊？”
So if you haven't seen the movie, it's a romantic comedy…
‎所以如果你没看过 ‎那是一部浪漫喜剧片
where I play a celebrity chef who falls back in love with her childhood friend.
‎我饰演明星主厨 ‎重新爱上自己的青梅竹马
And in the movie,
‎在片中
my character hooks up with three different, very good-looking,
‎我那个角色的交往对象 ‎是三个个性迥异、长相俊俏
very iconic,
‎非常知名
very sexy Asian American men.
‎又性感满点的亚裔美国男士
I know, it's like, who wrote this thing, right? Like…
‎我知道，编剧是谁啊？这…
Whose idea was this?
‎是谁想的点子？
And while shooting, all of my girlfriends kept on asking me,
‎我的姊妹淘在拍片时一直问我
"Okay, Ali, on the DL,
‎“好，艾莉，你偷偷跟我说
you gonna hook up with one of your costars?"
‎你会跟其中一个演员拍拖吗？”
You know, I came this close…
‎其实我就差这么一点
to fucking the food consultant.
‎跟餐饮顾问搞上了
It was this 29-year-old Persian dude who had tattoos all over his arms
‎这位29岁的波斯猛男 ‎两只手臂上都是刺青
and his chest, and when the wind blew, oh my God,
‎胸前也是，风一吹来，天啊
he was so ripped, you could see everything.
‎他的肌肉超大，一览无遗
You could see the King's Hawaiian,
‎你可以看到简直像修图的腹肌
you could see the cum gutters pointing you straight to the kingdom of heaven.
‎可以看到人鱼线 ‎告诉你天国之门在哪里
You could see it all, you know?
‎一览无遗，懂吗？
And we spent one Sunday morning
‎我们用整个礼拜天早上
butchering 18 raw chickens.
‎宰了18只鸡
That shit was like the "Unchained Melody" scene from Ghost…
‎就像《第六感生死恋》里 ‎男女主角手拉坏的那一幕
but with salmonella.
‎只不过多了沙门氏菌
He had his arms wrapped around me,
‎他的双手环抱着我
and I almost sliced my hand off,
‎我差点剁掉自己的手
because I could feel his 29-year old dick getting hard up against my spine.
‎因为我感觉到他29岁的老二 ‎硬起来后贴着我的脊椎
Yeah.
‎对
See, the pussy can fake a orgasm, but the dick don't lie.
‎女人的妹妹可以假装高潮 ‎但是男人的老二很诚实
I felt that biology and that truth right up against my back.
‎我的背就能感受 ‎他的生理结构和那句话有多真
I did not feel violated.
‎我不觉得自己被他冒犯了
I felt victorious.
‎我觉得自己胜利了
I did.
‎真的
As, like, a 39-year-old woman with two C-section scars,
‎身为今年39岁 ‎又有两道剖腹疤痕的女人
I was like, "Oh my God, I am so powerful."
‎我心想：“天啊，我的力量真大
"I changed density, motherfucker, what!"
‎操你妈的，我出运了，瞎款！
"I am a wizard! I'm a blood bender! I could be in Avatar."
‎我是大法师！ ‎我是截血神通！我可以当神通王
"Let's go, Appa. Let's go find Zuko and make out! Let's go!"
‎来，阿霸，我们去找朱克王子 ‎跟他恩爱一下！我们走”
And I went back to my hotel that afternoon
‎我那天下午回饭店时
and I pull down my pants,
‎把小裤裤拉下来一看
and my underwear…
‎我的小裤裤…
looked like the bottom of a bird cage.
‎看起来就像鸟笼的底部
It's a mystery to me why Hello Kitty hasn't contacted me yet, you know?
‎真不知道为什么凯蒂猫 ‎还没跟我联络，对不对？
It's like,
‎我心想
come on, what's up?
‎拜托，怎么回事？
‎我看到内裤变成那样 ‎看着那团黏呼呼的渣时
When I saw that in my underwear, when I saw those loogies,
I was like, "Oh my God, I still got it!"
‎我心想：“天啊，我还行耶…”
There is still supply, given that there is fresh demand, okay?
‎因为有新鲜需求 ‎所以我还能供应，好吗？
If you don't understand the supply and demand metaphor,
‎如果你不懂供应和需求的比喻
what I'm trying to tell you is my body still produces pussy juice, people.
‎我的意思是我的身体还能产生爱液
Okay? And it was good pussy juice too.
‎好吗？而且是上等爱液
It was sparkly and glistening.
‎闪亮动人
Viscous but not too pasty.
‎有点黏又不会太黏
Pungent but not too dank, it was…
‎有点腥又不会太腥，真是
It was.
‎极品
I took a little fun dip in there,
‎我因为好玩，稍微尝了一下
that shit tasted like LaCroix Pamplemousse.
‎那东西就像名牌葡萄柚汁
It was quality.
‎一流的
It could've sealed up all the holes in my underwear like Gorilla Glue, it was…
‎就像金钢固力胶一样 ‎能补好我内裤上的所有破洞
You know, as much as I would love to cheat on my husband,
‎虽然我很想让我老公戴绿帽子
I cannot afford to get a divorce.
‎但是我付不起离婚的代价
I can't, you know?
‎真的，你们懂吗？
The reality is, I need my husband way more than he needs me.
‎其实我比较需要我老公 ‎他却没有那么需要我
It is ten times harder to find a decent husband
‎找个还可以的老公
than it is to find a great wife.
‎比找个伟大的老婆还要难十倍
It's so fucking annoying, you know?
‎真他妈的讨厌耶
I'm almost 40, so I have all these, like, acquaintances getting divorced right now.
‎我快40岁了，所以认识很多离婚的人
All these women, they keep coming up to me…
‎这些女人老是跟我说
"Ali, it is so difficult dating out there for a divorced woman."
‎“艾莉，离过婚的女人超难找对象
"None of these men can handle me, a strong woman."
‎这些男人都没办法搞定我这个女强人
"None of these men want a strong woman."
‎这些男人都不要女强人”
I'm like, "You're an annoying woman, but…"
‎我心想：“你是个女烦人，不过…”
I do believe that it's slim pickings out there, you know?
‎我的确认为选择有限，懂吗？
And then these women, they keep telling me about their battle
‎这些女人又一直说自己的奋斗过程
and how ugly it is, how they're fighting for full custody of their kids.
‎离婚过程多丑陋 ‎她们如何争取孩子的单独监护权
I'm like, "Why?"
‎我就想：“干嘛啊？”
Even half custody sounds like American Horror Story.
‎连共同监护权 ‎都像《美国恐怖故事》了
I can't let go of my husband, you know?
‎我不能放生我老公，懂吗？
He's very handsome, he's very sexy, he's very much my type.
‎他超级帅、超级性感 ‎完全就是我的理想型
I have a very specific type.
‎我要的型非常具体
I like dudes who look as close to Keanu Reeves as possible.
‎我喜欢跟基努李维越像越好的男人
Yeah.
‎对
And that's my husband, straight up.
‎我老公就是这样
He's so good-looking, he's so interesting.
‎他长得好看、个性风趣
He speaks three different languages.
‎会说三种语言
He introduced me to mushrooms and ayahuasca,
‎还把迷幻蘑菇和死藤水介绍给我
changed my life.
‎改变我的一生
So in addition to being my husband,
‎所以他除了是我老公
he's also my drug dealer.
‎也是我的药头
I can't lose that Shaman connect, you know?
‎我不能放弃那个起乩的感觉，懂吗？
My husband's so smart.
‎我老公超级聪明
He went to Carnegie Mellon,
‎他念名校卡内基美隆大学
Harvard Business School.
‎哈佛商学院
He's a Fulbright scholar.
‎还是傅尔布莱特计划学者
He was smart enough to choose me, to invest in me,
‎更聪明到懂得选我，投资在我身上
when I was 20 pounds heavier,
‎我那时比现在还胖9公斤
had chronic acne and no money.
‎一直长痘痘，而且穷得要命
He bought low.
‎他低价买进
And if we get divorced, he going to sell high.
‎如果我们离婚，他就会高价卖出
I can't let him get away with that!
‎我不能让他占这个便宜！
So my husband, he's all of these wonderful things, right?
‎所以我老公有这么多优点，对吧？
But most importantly, he gives me permission
‎但是最重要的是，他愿意让我
to be myself.
‎发挥自己的本色
Which perhaps, for a wild, untamable spirit,
‎也许对狂野不羁的女人来说
is the most important quality to find in a man.
‎这才是理想老公最重要的特质
But people think it's so difficult for my husband
‎但是大家觉得就算只是
to do something so simple as giving me permission to be myself.
‎愿意让我发挥本色 ‎我老公都过得非常可怜
They always ask him, "Oh my God,
‎他们老是问他：“天啊
how do you feel about your wife Ali going up on stage
‎你对你老婆艾莉上台
in front of all of these strangers,
‎在一堆陌生人面前畅谈
talking about how much she wants to cheat on you?"
‎自己有多想让你戴绿帽有何想法？”
You know, right now while we're all here,
‎现在，我们人在这里
my husband is at home in the house that I bought…
‎我老公却在我买的房子里
telling time on the Rolex I got him for Father's Day…
‎用我在父亲节送他的劳力士表看时间
jacking off to porn that he streams
‎还对着网路A片打手枪
on the high-speed internet I pay for every month.
‎那个宽频上网月费还是我缴的
So, he always tells me…
‎所以他经常告诉我
"Yeah, you go ahead, you know you…"
‎“好，你就尽管说吧”
He doesn't give a shit about what I say on stage
‎他根本就不鸟我在台上讲的话
because he's too busy
‎因为他忙着
living the life I wanted for myself.
‎过我自己想过的生活
I'm the one leaning in while he is lying down.
‎我在承担责任，他负责躺平
And now that I'm the clear breadwinner,
‎现在我是货真价实的家庭支柱
he don't choke me like he used to.
‎他也不像以前那样掐我脖子了
It's too high stakes if I die.
‎因为我死的话损失太大
I'll be like, "Harder, come on, harder!"
‎我会说：“用力点，快点，用力！”
And he'll be like, "But I really want a PS5."
‎他会说：“可是我真的很想要PS5
"It's all sold out, and the waitlists and the ports are all full."
‎现在全都断货，要等超久 ‎而且到处都在塞港”
People like to assume that because my husband is very spiritual
‎大家老是以为因为我老公很虔诚
and because he's Asian American, that he's some kind of softy,
‎因为他是亚裔美国人，所以很软趴趴
when the truth is he got this backbone made of pure, solid steel.
‎其实他这个人根本就铁石心肠
He is a motherfucker.
‎他妈的超强悍
And whenever we get into an argument
‎我们每次吵架时
and I raise my voice,
‎只要我嗓门大了一点
he'll look me in the eye and say to me,
‎他就会瞪着我说…
"Oh, you don't talk to me like that."
‎“你不能用这种语气跟我讲话”
And then I'll be like…
‎然后我就会说…
"I'mma suck your dick."
‎“我要帮你吹喇叭”
"You put me in my place again."
‎“你又让我知道自己是什么身分了
"And then you give me permission to be myself,
‎而且你让我发挥自己的本色
and then you tell me what to do,
‎又告诉我该怎么做
and then you celebrate me."
‎然后又称赞我”
And that, single people, is what a healthy marriage looks like, okay?
‎各位单身男女 ‎这才是健康的婚姻关系，好吗？
I've been Ali Wong, have a good night, everybody. Thank you!
‎我是黄艾莉，大家晚安，谢谢！
‎（献给妮姬）
‎字幕翻译：温凤祺